What happens when you initialize a repository? Why do you need to do it?
creates new repository
Identifies status of programs
~ commits
How is the staging area different from the working directory and the repository? What value do you think it offers?

he staging area is a file, generally contained in your Git directory, that stores information about what will go into your next commit. It's sometimes referred to as the “index”, but it's also common to refer to it as the staging area.

writing commits
Type,
Body,
Footer
Type as new feature
fix a bug fix
docs changes to docs
style formatting, missing semi colons, etc
refactor refactoring production code
test adding tests,
chor updating build tasks, package manager configs,

Subject: what a commit does rather than what it did
Body: optional when a bit of explanation is required

